

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Bolu/Turkey

Summary

As a result-oriented Frontend Developer, I focus on improving user experience and aesthetics in web design. I stay updated with the latest technologies, software, and tools to deliver perfect functionality and visual appeal. Additionally, I enhance my skills by using Python and R for analytical thinking and machine learning algorithms to produce data-focused solutions that meet users' need

Work Experience

Saka Soft. Co., Ltd. Istanbul, Turkey

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

June 2021 - Oct. 2023

- As a frontend developer, it is important for me to create a clean and organized codebase when writing code. I follow clean code principles and the SOLID architecture to enhance the readability and maintainability of the code. Additionally, I use formatters to ensure consistent code formatting. These help provide clarity and context, especially in complex sections of the code.
- I prioritize clean, well-structured code that adheres to clean code principles and follows coding standards like the Airbnb style. I implement effective error-handling mechanisms to ensure smooth application operation.
- Developed various web applications using React and Next JS.
- · Created responsive designs using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Used the necessary tools and methods for SEO optimization.

OCG Biotecnology. Co., Ltd.

Istanbul, Turkey

DATA SCIENTIST Nov 2020- Jun 2022

- Responsible for data analytics and machine learning projects.
- He produced data analytical solutions using programming languages such as Python and R.
- Used data mining, basic statistics, machine learning and data visualization techniques
- · Cleaned, converted and preprocessed datasets.

Frontend Developer

CITIOAPP

SAKA SOFT

- CitioApp is designed as a website that enables all guests coming to Istanbul and Turkey from abroad to plan and access all the facilities in advance.
- https://citioapp.com/

ROMA SOLUTION

SAKA SOFT

- The sales website of Roma Solution was the start-up that would handle external projects in a separate entity.
- https://www.romasolution.com

AVIS AGRI

SAKA SOFT

- Avis Avgri is a website built around the sale of drones, incorporating reservation and online sales processes. Firebase and Next.js have been utilized in its development.
- https://avisagri.com

MEDIOAPP

SAKA SOFT

- A website that will be used to connect people who come from abroad and receive medical treatment in Turkey with hospitals. Written with NextJS.
- https://medioapp.com/

LOS BUTIK

FREELANCER

- It was prepared with next js as the e-commerce website of the women's clothing store in Bolu. React js was used for the panel.
- https://losbutik.com/

BROCCOLI

SAKA SOF

- Scraping and optimization of data on potential buyers for a new health kit that will be used in the beauty industry. Price recommender system based on location.
- https://procoli.com

Skills_____

Programming Language

- Javascript
- Python
- R

Technologies

- React JS
- Next JS
- Django
- Node JS

CSS

- SASS
- LESS
- Tailwind
- Bootstrap

Databases

- MongoDB
- PostgreSQL

Libraries

- · Socket.io
- Redux
- Gulp
- Webpack

VCS

- Git
- Bitbucket

Task

- ManagementJira
 - Agile
 - Scrum

Other

- Macos
- Ubuntu
- English

Data Scientist

Kaggle Competetions

PLAYERS SALARY FORECAST

 The variables affecting the salary of basketball players playing in the NBA provided by Kaggle are given. When making salary estimates of these players, artificial neural networks, K neighbor regression and decision trees regression were used. lasso was used for regularization.

OCG BIOTECNOLOGY

COVID-19 PREDICTION

 Trained a Logistic Regression model to predict whether a patient is Covid positive using PCR machine data, reducing time cost by 99 percent.

Kaggle Competetions

VEHICLE CONSUMPTION FORECAST

 XGBoost, Lasso, Ridge, ElasticNet, Linear regression models were used in the analysis of vehicle fuel consumption with the data provided by the University of California Irvine campus (UCI). At the same time, the achievements of the NCA and PCA methods, which are regularization methods, were compared.

Kaggle Competetions

BREAST CANCER FORECAST

 In the analysis of the data of patients with breast cancer provided by Kaggle, it was estimated using the KNN classification algorithm by applying the principal component method for size reduction.

Education

Bartin University

Bartin, Turkey

B.S. IN MOLECULAR BIOLOGY AND GENETICS

Oct. 2016 - Jun. 2020

 Project: Analysis and statistical calculations using python with zone diameter variables to study the effects of Alcanna Tinctoria plant on burn scar tissue using linear regression.

University of LodzLodz, PolandB.S. IN APPLIED BIOINFORMATICSFeb. 2018 - Aug. 2019

• Project: Investigation of FASTA formats and primer design of related gene sequences using snakemake, a bioinformatics workflow application.

Extracurricular Activity_

Molecular Biology Turkey

Online, Turkey

HEAD

Feb. 2020 - Nov. 2022

• Webinars were made by bringing together leading people with students in companies owners, academicians and similar institutions.

Bargenetech Bartin, Turkey

HEAD Oct. 2019 - Mar. 2020

• to provide students with research skills. Motivational seminars and personal development seminars were held before the exams.